COLIN MARETSKY

cjmaret@gmail.com

New York, NY

Github

in Linkedin



SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with 3 years experience, who comes from a medical and teaching background. Created 10+ applications primarily with the MERN stack, yet able to adapt to a range of languages, and has worked in developer teams between 2 and 15 people. Focus on building powerful, secure applications with a fluid user experience, and commit to the idea that each project should be better than the last. When not coding, doing stand-up comedy, poorly.

SKILLS

React - Node.js - Javascript - Typescript - HTML5/CSS3 - Express.js - Next.js - Gatsby - GraphQL - MongoDB - Git - Github

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

History Muffin E-commerce Store - Live | Github - React / Next.js / Apollo / Keystone / Typescript / Stripe

- A full-stack online merchandise store that lets users purchase, sell, and search for 1000s of products
- Server-side includes user authentication, permissions, uploading product images, and making purchases through Stripe, migrated from CRA to Next with 80% improvement on FMP

The Confectionery - <u>Live</u> | <u>Github</u> - *React / Contentful / Apollo / Netlify*

- Created SPA frontend for NYC filmmaking company, increasing lead conversion by 15%
- Implemented content management system, and organized 13+ carousels featuring video and VR video players

Dotcot Investor/Startup Site - Live - React / Node.js / Express.js / MongoDB / Heroku / Mocha

- Developed investor feed page and 6+ value filter bar to fetch and filter selected startup cards from database
- Collaborated with and helped lead a team of 8 developers through Agile methodology and CI/CD
- Engineered multi-faceted fetch requests and 2-tiered Mongoose queries to respond to user choices

PROJECTS

News Explorer Web App - Live | Github - React / Node.js / Express.js / MongoDB

• Developed a news search engine that allows users to view and save 5M+ articles to read at a later time, and collected data with RESTful APIs based on keywords, storing user data in MongoDB

Around the US App - <u>Live</u> | <u>Github</u> - *React / Node.js / Express.js / MongoDB*

- Built an Instagram-style page in which user can CRUD 1000s of personal photos, and like other users' photos
- Incorporated authorization component for user data, hosted on Google Cloud Platform, and stored 100s of images in MongoDB

WORK HISTORY

Full-stack Web Developer - Full-stack Developer - Jan 2020 to Present

- Developing, optimizing, and maintaining applications for 4+ companies, addressing clients' concerns over layout, scope, and cost
- Designing, structuring, and leading workflow amongst teammates for 2+ projects using CI/CD and best collaborative practices

Askademy English Center - Academic Manager - Dec 2016 to Jan 2018

• Coordinated and led a team of 15 teachers among 5+ grade levels, strove for 20% reduction of extraneous curriculum

Various Institutions - ESL Teacher - Jul 2016 to Jan 2020

• Prepared over 200 students for IELTS and TOEFL examinations, and managed classrooms of 30-55 students

Hunter EMS - Emergency Medical Technician - Jan 2014 to May 2016

- Delivered life support and critical care transportation to patients on 2500+ calls
- Prepared to perform 50+ critical care skills on emergent calls, necessitating performance under pressure

EDUCATION

Practicum by Yandex - Full-stack Web Developer Program - 740+ hours

John Jay College, CUNY - Bachelor of Arts in Forensic Psychology - Sept 2014 to Jun 2016

VOLUNTEER

Ambulance Exchange of the Islips - Emergency Medical Technician - Jan 2014 to May 2016